now he said look he or she who is not
angry when there's just cause for anger
sins yeah that's wrong it's a totally
human and blessed reaction to feel anger
when there is injustice he had a little
car early corollary that he yeah he he
said the opposite of the virtual angular
is what he called unreasoned patience
now that's the best translation from the
lab on recent patients and that means
that when there's cause for anger you
prefer to be patient long story short I
would like to advertise the virtue of
anger that within reason it's not only
totally acceptable but it's totally and
that when people see what's happened to
Susie they should be angry and if
they're not they're not virtuous and
anger should motivate some kind of well
some kind of feeling or a determination
to help out just as you know the analogy
that Vivian used do you help somebody
who needs help even when people are
reluctant to ask for that kind of help
so I've learned a lot from this
discussion and thanks for being for
bringing a real human dimension into it
but I would appeal to everyone including
Susie to be appropriately angry
otherwise you know you're not practicing
that virtue and obviously I think that's
brilliant what you just said and I'd
like to add a little phrase here not
trying to sort of guilt people I'm just
trying to identify specifically there
are crimes and then there are crimes of
omission where you did nothing right and
I think that that's what we're all doing
here we're all trying to do something
and when we see
one of our friends in trouble we go
there and help like when there was a
hurricane here in Florida I went to my
neighbor's I gave this old woman my
charger so that she didn't have to sit
in her house because she couldn't leave
and wouldn't leave without her phone
working so I gave her my little battery
charger you know afterwards when my all
my fences were blown over my neighbors
came over and helped me clean all the
wood in all the crack away we help each
other it's a human quality that just
breaks my heart when I see it happening
in this instant Susie needs our help
it's something
I wouldn't go so far to say it's a crime
of omission but I would certainly say
it's camaraderie and it's something that
if we don't all stick together and help
each other particularly when one person
is in tremendous need like like Julian
was Julian was in incredible danger and
Susie spearheaded this incredible
explosion of putting him back into you
know what would be the right I mean look
we all know what it means for somebody
to be disappeared well you can be
disappeared now electronically and
that's just as dangerous because nobody
knows anything about you and then
anything can happen to you and Susie we
need to help her and that's really all
I'm saying and I think what would you
know ray is saying it's just something
we all understand we all understand that
we need to be angry about these people
that are being attacked and not angry in
a stupid way where we like not people
when we see them I mean angry like we do
something about it we act and if anyone
wants to understand a little bit more
about the reality that we live in
I really do suggest you read the CIA
coup but it's Declassified now because I
swear to god the techniques that they
are using on interrogating they're using
on mass to control people
we need Susie because we need people
that are able to intelligently look at
what's happening in the world because
you will not get that information from
normal mainstream news media and brave
yeah just to underscore what you've just
said that the kubark manual goes well
beyond my time before my time but
William Casey who is the Reagan CIA
director said this in his first his
first pronouncement at the White House
and I have a friend who was there to
hear this he said we'll copy this down
with your with your principal quote
we'll know that our disinformation
Graham is complete when everything the
American public believes period and
quote whoa did you say that yes have an
eyewitness she actually told the
journalists at the time the journalist
was a wonderful person
her name was Sarah McClendon so this is
Casey early February 1981 and now that's
what a mission accomplished Americans
all believe what the deep state shadow
government wants him to believe so no
Moses to do the kinds of things that
will support people like Susie yeah but
I just wanted a bit of light in the
tunnel here not everybody believes it
and I think more and more people I think
this Epstein thing unless you're an
absolute like comatose being I think
everyone went wow he killed himself
really two days after he changes his
will where some strange Russian guy is
the the beneficiary of his 578 million
dollar estate did you hear about this
this is insane anyway this is not
relevant to Susie but all I'm just well
it is relevant to Susie because the
things that I'm gonna say for the 15th
time Susie needs our help she deserves
our help and you know what we need her I
need her we all need these people who
have a gift and she does have a gift not
only to examine and process information
but to write brilliant articles and we
need to help her right now because these
bloody you know elites have cut off her
income stream and Kraig has a real
opportunity to win a case very
appropriately into a grander strategy of
which we will all benefit from because
it really is this simple if we allow
people like Susie to go down the tubes
believe it we are going to go oh hi
kisses let the dog that day
if you can restart it go for it because
I'll just do the cool tech about I'll
just do three prints on what we
you
hi my name is Susie I'm an activist and
a journalist from Auckland New Zealand
for years I've worked on controversial
issues like the corruption of our
intelligence
I say goodbye it's your choice you can
stay or go is totally up to you thank
you everybody
I'm so sorry that like my donation page
apparently the stream also went down not
particularly surprising but unfortunate
we are back now I'll let Vivian and Ray
wrap up their thoughts and then I will
just give you the quick three-minute
calls to action about what it is we want
to achieve with this campaign and how
we're going to do it and then we'll say
goodnight everyone thank you so much for
being with us through all of these
issues what are your final thoughts and
Ray yours also my final thoughts are I
loved you Susie you're an amazing human
being
and I know there's so many people out
there that know how special and
important you are and whatever you can
afford if it's one dollar five dollars
fifty dollars five hundred five thousand
fifty thousand whatever it is she needs
that help as does Craig because in order
for any law fair - well thank you so
much for being here it really means so
much that you have my back and you've
been an incredible support for me
yourself and Christine right throughout
and I deeply deeply deeply appreciate
that
right what are your final scramming well
I just want to say that the kind of
people who are supporting you
exemplified by Craig who's been with us
here all this time the very encouraging
thing for me you've got you've got the
best of the best not only the best
intention but the best qualified and so
I feel privileged to be part of this to
the degree I can help you know that I'll
do it and I hope that other people trip
in because as Vivian said the stakes are
high and with Julian behind bars and you
still willing and able and courageous
enough to to apply
or trade as a journalist well that's a
big benefits what's all and with great
support no yeah yeah I think what John
Kiriakou is optimism as expressed before
is warranted so thanks for having having
me part of this and I look forward to
getting more with great
thank you so much for you and John have
just been you John Kerry aku have been
relentless support for me and pure
solidarity as well and I thank you so
much for that ok run so just really
clear about what the objectives of this
movement are from my perspective and
certainly my from will start with my
Russian legal team from their
perspective they want me to get refugee
status and they want it stat because
refugee status is what will prevent me
from living under threat of detention
and deportation secondarily we want
Asylum status because achieving
temporary asylum will give me a
temporary residency which will mean my
kids can go to school I can use the bank
in the post office and all the basic
public services that you really need to
have access to and what have any kind of
standard of living and to be able to
earn money again and to be able to be a
productive citizen again not that my
journalism and activism isn't being a
productive citizen but you think you
guys understand what I mean so those are
the two things from the immediate legal
perspective then the third thing is that
we want redress we want justice and
that's where Craig tuck comes in because
we over the coming months will be um
executing a series of plans strategic
litigation as Craig would say to try to
get that redress and to try and hold the
people who destroyed my life and New
Zealand's accountable for what they did
to myself my chill and not just it's not
just myself and my children it's my
entire family
I don't speak often about my family but
my parents who are both retired and have
kept me alive with their retirement
savings for a long time now and that is
incredibly difficult for them and to
come from lower middle class to
middle-class background growing up my
parents worked for 35 years for to have
those savings to be able to sustain
themselves during that retirement and so
my goal if I ever managed to
tree any of the funds that have been
cost me which because I did it cost me
my house and my everything I owned all
of my assets that I had in New Zealand
and not to mention my sizable income has
been the financial impact of the
targeting of me if I ever do get that
back right absolutely and will be paying
on my parents back the funds that they
have had to take from their retirement
in order just to keep myself and the
kids in one piece and still able to
function other friends and family have
also supported me and that's the only
reason I'm still sitting here today is
that I've had that support and I am
eternally conscious of how many
activists don't have that how many
homeless activist students even though I
that I worked with in New Zealand who
were targeted who didn't have any family
support whatsoever and those there are
for every one of me that is sitting here
able to dodge a campaign like this and
able to fight you know looked to have
legal fights in to seek redress there
are thousands of us that make it that
far there are activists who kill
themselves activists who are killed
there are activists who burn out who
could bankrupt or hospitalized who are
institutionalized
there are thousands and I really am so
privileged and lucky to even have made
it this far to still be able to function
at all I am so so so so privileged so I
want to acknowledge all of those people
that don't have what I have and haven't
been able to make it out of their
situations of being physically targeted
um I want to knowledge all of the people
that have come together to make this a
success not just those who are on the
stream tonight but the many activists
behind the scenes who have been doing
all kinds of things to even get us to
the point of launching this campaign
because I consider even to have a
campaign launched to be a success
despite the fact that we haven't yet met
that aims so that's my primary
consideration as getting refugee status
which is going to require engaging with
the UNHCR internationally because we've
been completely
at the local level and applying some
political pressure of our own back to
make that happen and then hopefully
being able to successfully file my new
asylum application here on the 27th and
present a new evidence and and follow
that pathway the third thing is
obviously we have got to raise financial
support not just because I face eviction
every month if I don't pay my rent but
because in order to pursue legal redress
and remedy is going to cost likely
hundreds of thousands of dollars but
certainly tens of thousands of dollars
it has to be an expensive and long
process this campaign is going to have
to run into the years rather than the
months and so we need to if we want to
have these big wins if we want to set
precedents if we want to hold these
agencies to account it's going to have
to be sustained and continuous
fundraising going on from this point to
be able to resource that fight and if we
win it I can guarantee you every dollar
that we've had to spend will be worth it
because it is time it's time that these
people were no longer allowed to get
away with the crimes that they have been
perpetrating against citizens and not
just myself I'm thinking of every person
I've known who's been targeted and every
person I don't know who has targeted and
I believe into the millions worldwide so
I mean we know there's two million on
the FBI watch list in America and that's
just for starters let alone
internationally so those are the first
three things in order refugee status
Asylum status and funding for sustaining
myself and my children but more
importantly the legal campaigns going
forward to achieve redress now tactical
things that you can do especially if you
can't give money and you don't feel able
to assist the legal campaign in any way
there's really basic things you can do
which is just tweeting sending messages
to the hashtag raising awareness on
social media following the Facebook
account 1vs5 a are following the Twitter
account looking at the website the
website one
Viacom has a whole list of things that
you could do actions that you can take
sharing that short seven-minute campaign
video that was a beginning of the stream
and that will play again at the end of
the stream it's an amazing thing put
together a huge amount of work went into
it I've got to shout out Quinn Peterson
propaganda propaganda and Copa Ramirez
Oh two of them worked for six eight
weeks to put that video together and it
is the most professionally produced
video today explaining what I was
blowing the whistle on and showing the
chronology of how they do Benchley came
to light and was proven and became
public record in New Zealand and
campaign so just take if you want to be
a part of this take those steps now
here's the big one though if you want to
actually join the campaign team if you
want to work with me and that other
activists are involved in this campaign
you can do so by going to 1vs5 i.com
slash discord d.i.s.c.o rd and i'm sure
also in social media admins will put
that link out now if you click on that
link you it will open the discord chat
application and it will take you to the
1vs5 i chat server and in there you'll
find a whole bunch of channels
organizing channels around this campaign
and you'll see there's news channels and
announcement channels for the latest
updates on the campaign so you can track
the progress of it and things to share
on social media you'll find graphics
channels for making memes and graphics
and support the campaign and video
channel for cutting short videos of
streams and doing promo videos there is
a whole bunch of different ways that you
can contribute tech stuff website stuff
all types of things so you don't need to
have money to be a part of this you
don't even need to donate $1 to be part
of this you can donate some time you can
donate some skills you can skill share
with people and they care and I can tell
you that you will meet the best people
being a part of something like this one
of the most beautiful things about doing
uni for Jay last year was watching
people come together and form
relationships
with each other work on a little sub
projects together and then take their
experience of working with each other
and go into other projects as a result
countless new connections were made
between people and countless other
projects and endeavors and resulted from
people simply meeting each other in the
unity forge a server and working on that
campaign so we're going to replicate
that again with one versus flyby and I
invite all of you to be a part of it
you'll discover that our work spaces our
discord workspaces I tightly governed
know like they're all business or down
to work we're friendly with each other
we hang out with each other but it's not
somewhere you'll find trolling you won't
find time leasing and you won't find BS
and there's really really refreshing
because we've managed to create an
environment that is productive and that
is friendly without having a lot of the
drawbacks of in-person organizing spaces
that you see in grassroots activism can
improve a rocky road and fortunately in
the digital space we have a cleaner
version of that so please come and be
part of it work with us and this is just
the beginning of what's going to be a
really really really long fight but a
really important one for all of us so I
think they said I want to say thank you
to Craig Craig Chuck has given me hope
fundamentally he has given me hope that
I didn't have before he's given me the
capacity to see a future where there is
justice and where there is redress and I
truly had lost hope of that prior to
this thank you brave what you said
before about the you know as someone
said in chat actually since they said a
judge a person by the company they keep
and that I'm in really good stead when
you know the measured on that front and
that's so so true I am really lucky to
be surrounded by people that I look up
to people who are more experienced than
me more qualified than me
and who stand by me and have my back
that is priceless absolutely priceless
and similarly priceless is the fact that
I've managed to build platforms and an
audience and that in many cases eclipses
the platform's and audiences of
traditional outlets who have basically
blacklisted me or just covered up my
situation for years now being Julian
Assange has the quarter-million rates on
it I don't think there's any article in
New Zealand media that has a
quarter-million rates on it and that's
because people really do care they care
about the truth they care about the
content and when they see the truth that
resonates with them and that that's what
I put it down to I don't think it's
particularly I really think it's like
skill on my part so much as there is the
reasoning the truth resonating with
people and this campaign is entirely
about truth and it's about protecting
people protecting our society and trying
to stop regular citizens being attacked
by the military complex so thank you in
advance to everybody who takes that leap
and jumps on board and becomes a part of
this it's ultimately because of all of
you that we will achieve anything from
this so thank you so much and I think
we'll wrap tonight final thank-yous as
to the tech team who have been
struggling to keep the stream up against
great adversity and thank you to watch
thousands literally thousands like this
scrolling at about 10 or 20 messages and
thousands and thousands and thousands of
messages being transmitted tonight about
this hashtag about this campaign
circulating all the information thank
you all for taking your time to do that
I deeply deeply appreciate it and I hope
that after we win this battle or maybe
even during that I can continue to
contribute
with my journalism and my activism in as
many ways as possible okay thank you all
and that's it from us for now bye-bye
good night
hi my name is Susie I'm an activist and
a gentleman
good night Craig good night ray I'm
gonna sign off Susie Wow hi my name is
Susie I'm an activist and a journalist
from Auckland New Zealand for years I've
worked on controversial issues like the
corruption of our intelligence agencies
I was severely targeted as a result of
my work this led to my articles being
amplified by the world's most
accomplished publisher in 2016 I made a
documentary about how and why I was
supposed to leave my country I have now
sought refuge in Russia and my situation
has become public 80 to 60 are the voice
of both it's 12:30 right now and Tony
with you and I'm really happy we finally
got through to a Moscow to my friend
over there Suzy Dawson you're listening
to a 95 b FM podcast Suzy Dawson is a
Kiwi activist and journalist who worked
as a member of Occupy Auckland's media
team at that time no five years later
and following involvement in GCSB and
TPPA opposition she's seeking asylum in
Russia a legend she has been spied on
harassed and threatened by the police
welcome back to the wire now finally on
the show today last week it was
announced that Suzy Dawson will be the
new leader of the Internet's party
wealth of the jimmy dore show we have a
special guest with us at Suzy Dawson
she's an activist journalist former
party leader and current president of
the internet party Suzy Dawson an
activist and citizen journalist
currently seeking asylum in Moscow Suzy
has written extensively on surveillance
and the deep state and claims it's not
safe for her in New Zealand
my name is Craig Turk I'm a lawyer from
New Zealand act in the area of
international human rights I act for
Susie Dawson along with a group of other
lawyers throughout the world who act for
journalists and dissenters and
high-profile cases including
the case of Julian Assange as far back
as 2012 Susie has been trying to warn
New Zealanders and other citizens around
the world about state targeting and
surveillance of citizens and the methods
being used to do it
[Music]
surveillance and new zealand's it's now
so widespread it's not an issue of
police going and getting a warrant and
doing an investigation and then it all
coming out in court
the vast majority is the surveillance is
undertaken is never going to be aired in
a courtroom and by that I'm talking
about cell phone technologies I'm
talking about lawful interception is the
term that the companies that through
this like to use there is a corporation
in Wellington New Orleans if if I caught
and you can google them and you can look
at their website and on their website
they're so good as to explain at links
exactly what they're doing and how legal
it is them to do it and essentially they
can intercept virtually any
communication if they have someone at
range they can hear your actual
conversations but also through cell
phones they can essentially turn them
into microphones and hear any
conversation that's had within vicinity
they can see you takes misters they can
see what photos are on your phone they
can see what files are on your phone
they can read your emails they can just
and spit all kinds of information
[Music]
any intelligence service in the world
that has significant funding and a real
technological research team can own that
phone the minute it connects to their
network as soon as you turn it on it can
be theirs they can turn it into a
microphone they can take pictures from
it they can take the data off of it but
it's important to understand that these
things are typically done on it too
basis not only was Susy essentially
blowing a whistle on state-level spy she
was named in the precise entities that
years later it would be proven had an
effect of being doing it and the fact is
the private corporations that are doing
it should be really concerning to us the
crowd that they got that they outsource
it to was pci/l with I believe Thomson
Clark
investigations limited this state is
contracting a private company to surveil
you to me that's really morals
absolutely immoral
some six years later in December 2018 an
official state services commission
report confirmed that New Zealand
government agencies had been employing
Thompson and Clark investigations
limited to target New Zealand citizens
this is a private company that have
essentially been instructed by state
agencies and departments to spy on
citizens
more than a dozen police staff are under
investigation for passing sensitive
information to the private investigators
Thompson and Claire Thompson in class
security firm Thompson and Clark
Thompson Clark so Thompson and Clark and
they aren't some of the old police
officers is there okay so does that
explain the relationship and the free
flow of information it doesn't it
actually seemed a bit crass well at the
end of the day I guess what I trust as
people's intent is the report identifies
perhaps an appropriately close
relationships morning teas paid for by
go out for drinks with the other
companies identified we you
inappropriately gave them information or
just Thompson and Clark there are a
myriad of security companies who inquire
of police every day for instance
Insurance Security that's not my
question people listening to this will
say hey Thompson and Clark we're giving
stellar top-shelf gold star treatment
from the police why do you treat other
security firms the same as you were
treating this one and how do you
seriously think it looks to two members
of the public listening to this Thompson
and Clark hasn't just been paid by the
government to spy on Greenpeace and
earthquake claimants in Christchurch
tonight checkpoint can reveal the
controversial security firm has been
also monitoring the activities of
another three activist groups and
Northland coromandel and Wellington and
the activities of at least one further
claimant Susie has been involved at the
very highest levels with people facing
charges from prosecution's coming out of
the Eastern District Court of Virginia
in the United States there are more
prosecutions to follow currently unnamed
persons importantly information will be
coming out in the months to come that
will provide transparency and clarity
and lead to accountability suppression
and prosecution of dissenters can't be
allowed in New Zealand or elsewhere
that's why Souza's teams launching the
hashtag 1vs5 eye campaign and with your
help can achieve some important
victories for democracy and for each and
every one of us
[Music]
you
hi my name is Susie I'm an activist and
a journalist from Auckland New Zealand
for years I've worked on controversial
issues like the corruption of our
intelligence agencies I was severely
targeted as a result of my work
this led my articles being amplified by
the world's most accomplished publisher
and 2016 I made a documentary about how
and why I was supposed to leave my
country I have now sought refuge in
Russia and my situation has become
public 82:6 PR the voice of birth it's
12:30 right now and Tony with you and
I'm really happy we finally got through
to a Moscow to my friend over there Suzy
Dawson you're listening to a 95 b FM
podcast Suzy Dawson is a Kiwi activist
and journalist who worked as a member of
Occupy Auckland's media team at that
time now five years later and following
involvement and GCSB and TPPA opposition
she's seeking asylum and Russia a legend
she has been spied on harassed and
threatened by the police welcome back to
the wire now finally on the show today
last week it was announced that Suzy
Dawson will be the new leader of the
Internet's party welcome the Jimmy Dore
show we have a special guest with us at
Suzy Dawson she's an activist journalist
former party leader and current
president of the internet party Suzy
Dawson an activist and citizen
journalist currently seeking asylum in
Moscow Suzy has written extensively on
surveillance and the deep state and
claims it's not safe for her in museum
my name is Craig tuck I'm a lawyer from
New Zealand act in the area of
international human rights I act for
Suzy Dawson along with a group of other
lawyers throughout the world who act for
journalists and dissenters in
high-profile cases including the case of
Julian Assange as far back as 2012 Suzy
has been trying to warn New Zealanders
and other citizens around the world
about state targeting in surveillance of
citizens and the myths being used to do
it
surveillance in New Zealand it's now so
widespread it's not an issue of police
going and getting a warrant and doing an
investigation and then it all coming out
in court
the vast majority is the surveillance is
undertaken is never going to be aired in
a courtroom and by that I'm talking
about cell phone technologies I'm
talking about lawful interception as the
term that the companies that through
this light to use there is a corporation
in Wellington New Zealand called Asus I
court and you can google them and you
can look at their websites and on their
website they're so good as to explain at
links exactly what they're doing and how
legal it is them to do it and
essentially they can intercept virtually
any communication if they have someone
at range they can hear your actual
conversations but also through cell
phones they can essentially turn them
into microphones and hear any
conversation that's had within vicinity
they can see you takes misters they can
see what photos are on your phone they
can see what files are on your phone
they can read your emails they can just
and spit all kinds of information
[Music]
any elegent service in the world that
has significant funding and a real
technological research team can own that
phone the minute it connects to their
network as soon as you turn it on it can
be theirs they can turn it into a
microphone they can take pictures from
it they can take the data off of it but
it's important to understand that these
things are typically done on a targeted
basis not only was Susy essentially
blowing a whistle on state level spying
she was naming the precise entities that
years later it would be proven had in
fact been doing it and the fact that
these are private corporations that are
doing it should be really concerning to
us the crowd that they got that they
outsource it to was pci/l with I believe
Thompson class investigations limited
the state is contracting a private
company to surveil you to me that's
really moral absolutely immoral some six
years later in December 2018 an official
State Services Commission report
confirmed that New Zealand government
agencies had been employing Thompson and
Clark investigations limited to target
New Zealand citizens this is a private
company that have essentially been
instructed by state agencies and
departments to spy on citizens
more than a dozen police staff are under
investigation for passing sensitive
information to the private investigators
Thompson and Claire Thompson in class
security firm Thompson and Clark so
Thompson and Clark
they aren't some of them old police
officers is there okay so does that
explain the relationship and the free
flow of information it doesn't it
actually seemed a bit crass well at the
end of the day I guess what I trust as
people's intent is the report identifies
perhaps an appropriately close
relationships morning teas paid for by
Thompson and Clark invitations to go out
for drinks with the other companies
identified were you inappropriately gave
them information or just Thompson and
Clark there are a myriad of security
companies who inquire of police every
day for instance insurance security
that's not my question people listening
to this will think hey Thompson and
Clark we're giving stellar top-shelf
gold star treatment from the police why
do you treat other security firms the
same as you were treating this one how
do you seriously think it looks to to
members of the public listening to this
Thompson and Clark hasn't just been paid
by the government to spy on Greenpeace
and earthquake claimants in Christchurch
tonight checkpoint can reveal the
controversial security firm has been
also monitoring the activities of
another three activist groups in
Northland coromandel and Wellington and
the activities of at least one further
climbers
Susy has been involved at the very
highest levels with people facing
charges from prosecution's coming out of
the Eastern District Court of Virginia
in the United States there are more
prosecutions to follow currently unnamed
persons importantly information will be
coming out in the months to come that
will provide transparency and clarity
and lead to accountability suppression
and prosecution of dissenters can't be
allowed in New Zealand or elsewhere
that's why Susy teams launching the
hashtag 1 vs. 5i campaign and with your
help can achieve some important
victories for democracy and for each and
every one of us
[Music]
you